<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visual Computing 2022-2</title><link>https://andresrperez12.github.io/VisualComputing2022-2/docs/workshops/</link><description>Recent content on Visual Computing 2022-2</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://andresrperez12.github.io/VisualComputing2022-2/docs/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://andresrperez12.github.io/VisualComputing2022-2/docs/workshops/3DApplication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andresrperez12.github.io/VisualComputing2022-2/docs/workshops/3DApplication/</guid><description>Workshop: Visual Illusions # Workshop 1
Implement a 3d webgl application. The p5.treegl or any other libraries may be used. Problem statement # Design and implement a 3D Application using WebGL, through some library or framwork based on it.
Background # WebGL # WebGL is an API for creating 3D graphics on web browsers without the need for any additional plug-ins, and is itself based on the OpenGL API. It uses the Canvas element from HTML to visualize the resulting graphics, and therefore is integrated with the DOM model.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://andresrperez12.github.io/VisualComputing2022-2/docs/workshops/maskingWorkshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andresrperez12.github.io/VisualComputing2022-2/docs/workshops/maskingWorkshop/</guid><description>Workshop: Masking # Workshop 2
Implement an image processing web app supporting different image kernels. Problem statement # Implement an image processing web app supporting different image kernels and supporting:
Image histogram visualization. Different lightness (coloring brightness) tools. Background # Image Kernel # In image processing, a kernel, convolution matrix, or mask is a small matrix used for blurring, sharpening, embossing, edge detection, and more. This is accomplished by doing a convolution between the kernel and an image.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://andresrperez12.github.io/VisualComputing2022-2/docs/workshops/visualIllussionsWorkshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andresrperez12.github.io/VisualComputing2022-2/docs/workshops/visualIllussionsWorkshop/</guid><description>Workshop: Visual Illusions # Workshop 1
Study, implement and discuss possible applications of some known visual phenomena and optical illusions. Problem statement # Identify, implement, and discuss possible applications of some known optical illussions on the design and development of computer graphics.
Background # Stroboscopic Artifacts # The color wheel displayed contains the three colors: red, green, and blue. When the angular speed of the rotation is turned up to 120° per frame, a strange effect can be seen.</description></item></channel></rss>